## Contact

jenjwatkins@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jenniferschieferle-uhlenbrock-dnp-mba-rntcrn-55550b7a (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Hospitals
Healthcare Management
Leadership

## Languages

German (Limited Working)
Sign Languages (Limited Working)
Spanish (Professional Working)

## Certifications

CITI

**NINR** 

Duolingo German Fluency: Elementary (Estimated)

**ENPC** 

ACLS

### Honors-Awards

Nominated for NCNA Political/ Legislative Award

Dennis Keller Academic Scholarship

Top Emergency Department Nurse

Sigma Theta Tau International Nursing Honor Society

President's List

#### **Publications**

Ask 3 Teach 3

# Jennifer Schieferle Uhlenbrock DNP, MBA, RN, TCRN

Clinical Educator at St Davids Health Care System Austin, Texas

# Summary

Excellence in practice, higher education, leadership, and research are the heart of my career development and professional philosophy. My experience in bedside nursing, marketing, and research has prepared me as a translational leader who can supervise, motivate, and develop staff. As an officer in a non-profit professional organization, I have experience with project management, monitoring productivity, and succession planning.

Specialties: mentor, preceptor, quality improvement projects, evidenced based practice, research committee, trauma committee, trauma certification, professional development, managerial economics, marketing, scientific approach, translational research, translational leader.

# Experience

St Davids Health Care System Clinical Educator December 2018 - Present (1 year 7 months) Austin, Texas Area

Duke University Hospital System
Registered Nurse
March 2014 - December 2018 (4 years 10 months)
Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

Emergency Department

Nominated for ANA State Political/Legislative Award 2016

Duke NEXT Ambassador

Duke AHEAD Program

Trauma & Critical Care Committee

Interview Committee

NC ENA Conference Delegate 2016, 2017

### NC ENA Day on the Hill Delegate 2017, 2018

WakeMed

Registered Nurse

February 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 5 months)

**Emergency Department** 

**Emergency Department** 

Inova Health System

Registered Nurse

August 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 7 months)

Emergency Department, System Float Pool

Methodist Health System

Resource Nurse

January 2011 - August 2012 (1 year 8 months)

Critical Care, MSICU, CV Step-down, IMIS, Tele, Renal, Ortho, Medical,

Surgical, Oncology, Neuro, Transplant, CDU, Suites

### **UTHSCSA**

Research Mentorship Program

May 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 3 months)

San Antonio, Texas Area

Vascular Surgery- Pathology

## Parallon

**Travel Nurse** 

January 2010 - January 2011 (1 year 1 month)

CCU, CV Step-down, IMIS

Achievers Professional Staffing LLC

**Independent Contractor** 

January 2007 - December 2009 (3 years)

Military, schools, LTACs, rehabs, surgical centers, boxing

HCA Rio Grande Regional Hospital

Registered Nurse/ Charge Nurse

January 2006 - December 2009 (4 years)

Telemetry, Employee Advisory Group (EAG)

South Texas Health System/McAllen Medical Center Practicum Student/Trauma Emergency Department June 2008 - August 2008 (3 months)

The region's designated Advanced Level III Trauma Center and provides exceptional care in treating many types of trauma. Host Air Evac Lifeteam.

# Education

Duke University School of Nursing

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Nursing Administration · (2016 - 2017)

Keller Graduate School of Management of DeVry University Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business Administration and Management, General · (2014 - 2015)

Chamberlain College of Nursing
Masters of Science, Executive Track · (2013 - 2014)

The University of Texas at San Antonio
Bachelor of Arts (BA), Literature & Philosophy (2010 - 2012)

The University of Texas-Pan American
Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing (2008 - 2009)